bernina.com 2018-11-16

# Privacy Policy - Footer - BERNINA

**1.  Your safety is our top priority**

At BERNINA, we are committed to respecting the privacy of the users of this website. This Privacy Policy, in conjunction with the Terms and Conditions of Use, forms the basis for the treatment of personal information. The paragraphs below provide information about the type of user information collected by BERNINA and how this information is used. BERNINA complies with applicable data protection rights at all times and only processes personal information for the purposes for which the information was provided. Responsibility for data processing lies with BERNINA International AG.

The Terms and Conditions of Use of the website and the legal requirements on privacy and data protection are adapted, supplemented or amended from time to time. Each time you access or visit the website, the versions accessible at that time apply. Please visit this page every time you visit the site to view the latest Terms and Conditions of Use.

By using this website, you acknowledge and consent to the use of your personal information as stated in this Privacy Policy. If you do not consent to these provisions, please do not provide BERNINA with any personal information.

**2 Collection of personal data**  
**2.1  Collection of personal data for informational use**

  On visiting the BERNINA website, there is no automatic collection of personal information about the user, such as name, address telephone number or email address unless this information is provided voluntarily by the user by filling in a form on the website or making contact with us in another way via the site. Data collection and analysis also applies to information you provide to us when you subscribe to one of our services or if you require other services. In addition, we may keep records of correspondence if you make contact with us.

  BERNINA constantly strives to make our website more interesting for all our users. For this reason, statistical visitor data is collected each time the website is visited to establish which pages of the website are visited most frequently by each user. This includes the collection of data regarding the browser, operating system, weblogs and other connection data used by the user, irrespective of whether its collection is required for our or other purposes. In this context, it is sometimes necessary to use cookies (More information about the use of cookies is available in section 3 of this Privacy Policy).

  **2.2 Collection of personal data for special uses**  
**2.2.1 Customer portal**

  If you wish to use our customer portal, you must first register by providing your name, your email address, and a password of your choosing. This information will be stored in the Microsoft Azure Cloud on servers in the EU. For this registration, we use for the so-called double opt-in process, which means your registration is not complete until you confirm the registration using a code sent to you by email. You must provide the aforementioned data to use the customer portal. You can voluntarily provide more information by using our portal.

  In our customer portal, you can view, change, and add to the personal information that we have on record for you at any time. We use this information for customer data management and, if necessary, to process any warranty claims as well as to personalize advertising. Additionally, you can register your Bernina products, sign up for the Bernina newsletter, and identify topics that you are particularly interested in.

  If you want to register a product, we will save the information you provide (serial number, date of purchase, dealer, product, and other information in the questionnaire) and use it for the purpose of customer data administration and, if necessary, to grant any benefits you may be awarded as a result of registering the product, and to provide personalized advertising.

  For more information on data privacy when using the newsletter service, please see section 2.2.2 Newsletter.

  Information that you provide in the customer portal may be linked to other information we have saved about you in a customer profile. In doing so, we comply with the principle of purpose limitation and link only data that has been collected for the same purposes (e.g. for advertising). Bernina can provide dealers, suppliers, or service providers with information from your customer profile if you have given your consent, which is revocable at any time, to this submission or if the transmission of this information is necessary in order to process your request. Bernina will only transmit your data to third parties to the extent required. These third parties are obligated to adequately protect your data and to use it in conformity with the law.

  You are neither legally or contractually obligated to provide information. Use of the customer portal, however, is only possible if the required information specified above has been provided. Any benefits arising from product registration can only be provided if the product has been registered.

  You can delete individual data stored in the customer portal at any time. All of your stored data may be deleted upon request. Additional information about your information and revocation rights is available in paragraph 9 of the data protection provisions. In all other respects, your data will be deleted when the purpose for which the data was collected no longer exists.

  **2.2.2 Newsletter  **

You can sign up for our newsletter to receive information about the latest trends in sewing, quilting, and embroidery as well as attractive offers from Bernina.

  The sign-up for our newsletter follows the so-called double opt-in process. This means that we send an email to the specified email address in which we ask you to confirm that you wish to receive the newsletter. If you do not confirm your registration within 7 days, your information will be automatically deleted. In addition, we will save your IP addresses as well as the dates of registration and confirmation. The purpose of this process is to verify your application and, if necessary, to clarify any possible misuse of your personal data.

  The only information required to send the newsletter is your email address. The submission of additional information is voluntary and will be used to personalize your experience. After we have received your confirmation, we will store your email address for the purpose of sending the newsletter.  
You can revoke your consent to receiving the newsletter and unsubscribe from the newsletter at any time. You can cancel by clicking on the link provided in each newsletter or by emailing [info@bernina.com](mailto:info@bernina.com).  

We hereby inform you that we evaluate your user behavior when sending the newsletter. To this end, a cookie is stored on your computer via a personalized link in the newsletter with a user ID so that we can identify you for future visits to our website. We link the data specified in section 2.1 with the user ID, your email address, and any stored data in a user profile. Using this data, we create or add to a user profile in order to tailor the newsletter to your specific interests. We record when you read our newsletter and which links you click in it. This allows us to infer your personal interests. We link this data with your actions on our website.

  You can object to this tracking at any time by sending an email to [info@bernina.com](mailto:info@bernina.com). This information will be stored as long as you are subscribed to the newsletter.

**3.  Use of cookies**

Like many other websites, BERNINA uses cookies on this website. Cookies are small pieces of text information, which are stored by your browser (e.g. Internet Explorer or Mozilla Firefox) on your computer's hard drive. These cookies are completely anonymized and contain no personal information. Most of the cookies used by BERNINA are deleted from your hard drive at the end of the browser session (so-called session cookies). Other cookies remain on your computer and make it possible for BERNINA to recognize your computer the next time you visit (so-called permanent cookies). Cookies simplify your use of the BERNINA website and are used to make the BERNINA website pleasant and easier to use in operating it. They are used, for example, in the Welcome involving your user name, make it easy to fill in forms with your data and remember your language selection or products in the shopping cart.

At no time is spy software installed or used to gain access to data and information stored on your computer.

Cookies make it easier for you to use the BERNINA website and contain no personal information about the user. Most browsers automatically accept cookies. However, you can configure your browser so that it does not accept or store cookies. Details of how to do this can be found in the operating instructions or help files of your browser.

If you opt out of the use of cookies, your ability to use every function on this website to its fullest extent could be limited.

**4.  Use of information**

The anonymized data that are retained when accessing our website via cookies can be used for purposes of analysis and for optimizing the website in conjunction with third party services. As a result, these third parties can - to a limited extent - themselves collect personal data about BERNINA users, provided that they recognize them, for instance, by means of their own cookies or logins.

**4.1     Google Analytics**

The BERNINA website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google Inc. ("Google"). Google Analytics uses so-called "cookies", text files that are stored on your computer and enable your use of the website to be analyzed. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website is usually transmitted to and stored on a Google server in the USA. The IP address transmitted by your browser as part of Google Analytics will not be merged with other Google data. BERNINA has also activated the "anonymizeIP" configuration for Google Analytics on this website. This ensures that IP addresses are processed in truncated form, to prevent specific users from being identified. Only in exceptional cases will the full IP address be transmitted to a Google server in the USA and truncated there.

Google will use this information on behalf of BERNINA to analyze your use of the website for BERNINA, to compile reports regarding website activity and to provide other services related to website and Internet usage (in particular functions for display advertising, such as remarketing, reports on Google Display Network impressions, DoubleClick Campaign manager integration and Google Analytics demographic and interest reports).

Under certain circumstances, Google may analyze your usage behavior over several end devices (PC, smartphone, tablet etc.) and evaluate it for BERNINA using so-called cross-device functions. For this, Google may link information generated by the respective end devices for the purpose of personalized advertising with other such data and with data from your Google Account, if you have a Google Account and your preferences are set to allow Google to link the browsing history to the Google Account and use information from the Google Account to personalize the advertising you receive.

You can prevent Google Analytics cookies from being stored on your computer by selecting the relevant settings in your browser. However, please note that, if you do this, you may not be able to utilize the full functionality of this website. You can also prevent Google from collecting and processing the data generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including your IP address) by downloading and installing the browser plug-in available from the following link: <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

As an alternative to the browser plug-in or in browsers on mobile devices, you can click the following link to set an opt-out cookie that will prevent Google Analytics data collection from this website in the future (this opt-out cookie only works in this browser and for this domain; if you delete your cookies in this browser, you will have to click this link again): Click here to set your opt-out cookie.

**4.2     Google AdWords conversion tracking**

This website also uses Google AdWords conversion tracking, a web analysis service by Google, Inc., for improving the website and the advertising activities. The cookie for conversion tracking is set when a user clicks on an ad controlled by Google. These cookies become invalid after 30 days and are not used for personal identification. If you visit certain pages of our website within these 30 days, both we and Google in the USA can recognize that you clicked on the ad and were routed to this site. Every Google AdWords customer gets a different cookie. As a result, cookies cannot be tracked via the websites of AdWords customers. The information obtained by conversion cookies is used to generate conversion statistics for us. We learn the total number of users who clicked on our ad and were routed to our site. However, we do not receive any information by which you can be personally identified.  
If you do not want to participate in the tracking, you can simply disable the Google conversion tracking cookie in your web browser's user settings. In that case you are not included in the conversion tracking statistics. Additional setting options can be found on the web page about disabling Google ads at http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/.

**4.3    Use of A/B testing by Visual Website Optimizer**

Less frequently, the BERNINA website uses the Visual Website Optimizer web analysis service by Wingify Software Private Limited, Inc., which is used for A/B and multi-version tests. This service uses cookies to identify a user's browser and to analyze the use of this website. The cookies placed by Visual Website Optimizerv do not collect personal data.  
More information about how Visual Website Optimizer processes your data can be found at https://vwo.com/privacy-policy/. You can disable Visual Website Optimizer tracking at any time by following the instructions at https://vwo.com/opt-out/.

**4.4   Ignition One**

 BERNINA uses the Digital Marketing Suite (DMS), a service for web analysis by IgnitionOne Deutschland GmbH, Leonrodstr. 52, 80636 Munich, Germany. The DMS helps BERNINA to analyze user behavior while on bernina.com in order to improve and optimize the website and the provided content continuously.

  Using a tag that runs in the background of bernina.com, IgnitionOne collects information about user behaviors, such as product interests on the website. Once a page is opened, the following data will be transmitted to IgnitionOne: The complete URLs you loaded to enter the page, the page you visited before you entered the currently opened page, the time you stayed on our pages, browser type, operating system and device type,  cookie settings and the time you entered the page. Furthermore, we assign a user ID to you which is stored in a cookie on your browser, provided you accept cookies and you haven’t withheld your consent for analysing your behavior (appeal procedures are described below). With every click on a button or link an anonymous profile is updated based on the currently visited page and the page visited before. The profile information will be stored in the BERNINA user database on IgnitionOne servers within the European Union. Depending on the usage of the website, separate forms and offers may be displayed.

  You can deactivate cookies at any time. However, this might lead to the website not being able to be used without restrictions.  Alternatively, you can perform an opt-out at https://www.ignitionone.com/cookie-opt-out/. Once you’ve done this, IgnitionOne will delete all existing cookies and attempt to set a new one (no cookie tracking) in order to make sure that your deactivation of cookies is valid for future visits to the website. Furthermore, all data that has already been collected by the IgnitionOne data collection tag will be deleted. The no-track-cookie tells the IgnitionOne server that no further user analysis shall be created in the future. If your browser is configured in a way that cookies are not accepted in general, a no-track-cookie cannot be set. Furthermore, if you delete cookies or if you use a different browser or computer, you have to perform the opt-out procedure again.

If you have not disagreed with the use of cookies and fill out a contact form on the website, we will combine the data entered in the contact form with the data collected via the IgnitionOne tag. With regards to the aforementioned purpose, this data will be forwarded to IgnitionOne Deutschland GmbH and processed.

**4.5  Quantcast**

Furthermore, the BERNINA website uses a service by Quantcast, 795 Folsom Street, 5th Floor, San Francisco, CA 94107, to create individual, anonymous data profiles of our users. This involves a cookie from Quantcast which is set when the user enters the website.

  Quantcast only models anonymous records of Internet usage. Quantcast does not intentionally collect any personally identifiable information – that is, information that could be used to uniquely identify or locate an individual.

  Information collected by Quantcast may be used by BERNINA to understand the characteristics and demographics of the people who visit bernina.com.  Furthermore, this knowledge may be used to develop online advertising which is more efficient, pleasant, and relevant to the user’s interests.  

  More information about how Quantcast handles your data can be found at https://www.quantcast.com/privacy/. You can disable Quantcast tracking by disabling cookies within your browser. 

**4.6 Facebook Pixel**

  BERNINA of America uses a service by Facebook that involves a pixel installation on the website.

  Any customer data that BERNINA of America passes through the Facebook pixel is hashed locally on the browser before it goes to the Facebook servers for matching. This hashing process turns data collected from the BERNINA of America pixel into short encrypted messages that cannot be tampered with.

Facebook uses these hashes to match pixel events with people on Facebook. Then Facebook deletes all matched and unmatched hashes immediately after the matching process ends. Facebook does not collect or store any personally identifiable information on their servers.

The Facebook pixel uses secure https connection, so that any data transmitted from the browser will make it to the Facebook servers safely.

  Find more information about pixels data [here](https://developers.facebook.com/ads/blog/post/2016/05/31/advanced-matching-pixel/).

**4.7   Data sent to BERNINA**

Information that you provide to BERNINA yourself as a user of the website may be used by BERNINA and companies affiliated with BERNINA in order to improve the BERNINA website and to provide individual support to the user. This also includes sending the user items such as information, offers or notifications regarding BERNINA's product range and services.

**4.8   Server location**

The personal information collected is transmitted and stored in Austria (location of the server). The information will be treated in Switzerland and in accordance with the applicable Swiss data protection regulations. However, the information may be processed outside of Switzerland by personnel working for us or for our suppliers. By providing your personal information, you consent to the transmission, storage and processing of your information in accordance with these data protection regulations.

**5.   Social media content**

BERNINA may use social media plugins, e.g. by Facebook, Google+ and Twitter, on this website. These platforms have their own privacy policies over which BERNINA has no control.  
If you are logged in at a social media provider's site while simultaneously visiting our site, the possibility of the provider matching the visit to your network account cannot be ruled out. If you use the plugin functions (e.g. clicking on the "Like" button, posting a comment), this information is similarly transmitted from your browser directly to the particular social network and possibly stored there. The purpose and the extent of the collection, further processing and use of the data by the networks can be found in the privacy policy notices of Facebook, Twitter and Google.  
If the user does not want any of these plugins to be loaded, it is recommended to log out of the particular social media service. In addition, various browsers can be set or upgraded with add-ons (e.g. Facebook blocker) so that the social media plugins are not loaded.

**6.  Disclosure of information**

BERNINA and its subsidiaries and affiliates within the Group use your personal information in accordance with these data protection regulations and will not disclose it to third parties. 

Exceptions to this are if you have consented to the disclosure of information to companies not affiliated to BERNINA or if BERNINA is required by law, by a government authority or a court to do so. Another exception is if service providers are engaged to support BERNINA in data processing, administering the website or in another capacity or to provide you with products and services you have requested. These third parties are obliged to maintain the same degree of security and data protection as BERNINA.

  **7.  Children as users of the website**

A note to children and their parents: children are increasingly using the Internet. Parents should ensure that their children do not submit any personal information about themselves or their parents to BERNINA. However, if personal information is transmitted by children to BERNINA, we ask parents to contact BERNINA if they want the information to be deleted. The relevant information will then be deleted as soon as possible.

**8.  Data security**

The transmission of data over the Internet is unfortunately not absolutely secure. In order to protect your information, BERNINA only collaborates with service providers and Internet providers that take appropriate technical and organisational security measures. However, BERNINA cannot guarantee the security of the data transmitted by you as a user. Any transmission of data is undertaken at your own risk.

**9.  Your information and withdrawal rights**

You have the option of informing BERNINA at any time - for example, by email - that your information should in future no longer be used to contact you. You can also cancel your participation in particular services of the BERNINA website, such as the newsletter service, at any time.

In addition, you are also able to obtain information on the processing of information or to request a copy of your personal information that has been collected about you via our website. Please send your request in writing to  BERNINA International AG, Seestrasse 161, 8266 Steckborn, Switzerland or [info@bernina.com](mailto:info@bernina.com).

**10.  Final provisions**

If the individual provisions or parts of these Privacy Policy should prove to be invalid or ineffective, the validity of the rest of the Privacy Policy will not be affected.

The jurisdiction and applicable law are as stated in the Terms and Conditions of Use.

_Last updated: March 26th, 2018_
